<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title>Lallyx&#x27;s game dev adventures - Devlog</title>
    <subtitle>The blogging diary of a thirty-something dad who wants become an indie game dev</subtitle>
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://lallyx.github.io/tags/devlog/atom.xml"/>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lallyx.github.io/"/>
    <generator uri="https://www.getzola.org/">Zola</generator>
    <updated>2025-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://lallyx.github.io/tags/devlog/atom.xml</id>
    <entry xml:lang="en">
        <title>Inventory</title>
        <published>2025-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</published>
        <updated>2025-08-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
        
        <author>
          <name>
            Lallyx
          </name>
        </author>
        
        <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://lallyx.github.io/devlog/2025-08-01/"/>
        <id>https://lallyx.github.io/devlog/2025-08-01/</id>
        
        <content type="html" xml:base="https://lallyx.github.io/devlog/2025-08-01/">&lt;h1 id=&quot;inventory&quot;&gt;Inventory&lt;&#x2F;h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We&#x27;ve now got an inventory that allows for 2 types of items:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Usable&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collectable&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each item is setup as a resource in Godot with its related template, so that for any new ones I need to create I just need to reuse the template.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The template supports 2 types of interactions:&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use: press in the inventory and call a function to be executed&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Collect: used upon collection, without getting stored in the inventory itself.&lt;&#x2F;li&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To end up in the inventory, items (pickups) just need to enter in the player&#x27;s collision box.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are currently infinite inventory slots and infinite stacks as I first want to figure out what kind of items and how many do I want to put in the game.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The save system has been updated to transform the inventory resources into a structured JSON array that can be stored in a file and that can be loaded back in.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I banged my head on the wall for a few hours because when loading the game from the save file the button slots references got missed.
Who knew that emptying an array and using .clear() would have different results? :&#x2F;
Also, the more I look at this, the more this architecture is just poor.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Can I be bothered to redo it, not even knowing what my game will look like?
Nope.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The UI will need to be refined, as it&#x27;s just a grid for the time being (still looking fresh though!)&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When clicking around I found out that when adding buttons inside a grid you need to specify the minimum size, otherwise the icons get all funky.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The big disappointment in this development came from chatGPT, who insisted to use the remove() method for array slots, which doesn&#x27;t exist anymore in Godot4.
I felt stupid for a while, before it went off &quot;thinking&quot; and came back apologising.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gaslit by an AI, that must be something new.&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;&#x2F;devlog-resources&#x2F;recordings&#x2F;inventory.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Inventory&quot; &#x2F;&gt;&lt;&#x2F;p&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Show me what you got&lt;&#x2F;figcaption&gt;
&lt;&#x2F;figure&gt;</content>
        
    </entry>
</feed>
